Guide to the Liggett Family Papers TAM.463
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Liggett Family Papers
circa 1920-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Liggett, Edith Fleischer
Woodbury, Marda Liggett
Evans, Mark Walter
TAM.463
19.25 Linear Feet (20 boxes)
Walter William Liggett (1886-1935), American author, journalist and political activist from Minnesota, worked at several newspapers in New York City before becoming a free-lance writer. In New York, he worked for a succession of papers, including the Times, Sun, Post, News, and the Socialist publication, The Call. His writing career began during World War I at local papers-the Pioneer Press, Minneapolis Journal, and St. Paul Dispatch. In 1932 he returned to his home in Minnesota. A large portion of his time was spent promoting the Minnesota-based populist reform movement of the 1920s known as the Farmer-Labor Party, and working on publications for a Farmer-Labor newspaper, the Midwest American. On December 9, 1935, Liggett was gunned down in front of his wife and daughter in Minneapolis after exposing a connection between local organized crime and Floyd B. Olson, the progressive Farmer-Labor governor of Minnesota. In 1998, Marda Liggett Woodbury published an account of Liggett's life and assassination in a book titled Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett. The bulk of the collection includes material related to Marda Liggett Woodbury's research on the life and assassination of her father, Walter Liggett. The material consists of newspaper clippings, research files, and interviews. The collection also includes some family papers and photographs and published writings of Liggett's mother, Edith Fleischer Liggett.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mark Walter Evans in 2008. The accession number associated with this gift is 2008.054.
Historical/Biographical Note
Walter William Liggett (1886-1935), American author, journalist and political activist from Minnesota, worked at several newspapers in New York City, including the New York Times, Sun, New York Post, Daily News, and the Socialist publication, The Call, before becoming a free-lance writer. His writing career began during World War I at local papers: the Pioneer Press, Minneapolis Journal, and St. Paul Dispatch. In 1932 he returned to his home in Minnesota. A large portion of his time was spent promoting the Minnesota-based populist reform movement of the 1920s known as the Farmer-Labor Party, and working on publications for a Farmer-Labor newspaper, the Midwest American. On December 9, 1935, Liggett was gunned down in front of his wife and daughter in Minneapolis after exposing a connection between local organized crime and Floyd B. Olson, the progressive Farmer-Labor governor of Minnesota. In 1938, his widow, Edith Fleischer Liggett, sued Comprodaily Inc., the holding company that published the Communist Party newspaper, the Daily Worker, for libel. The prosecuting Attorney was Thomas E. Dewey, the district attorney of New York. After five years Edith Liggett won a judgment of $2500. In 1998, Marda Liggett Woodbury published an account of Liggett's life and assassination in a book titled Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett.
Scope and Contents note
The bulk of the collection includes material related to Marda Liggett Woodbury's research on the life and assassination of her father, Walter Liggett. The material consists of newspaper clippings, research files, and interviews. The collection also includes some family papers and photographs and published writings of Liggett's mother, Edith Fleischer Liggett.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Much of the collection is in poor condition and in need of re-housing, and thus may not be available for use.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Correspondence.; Communism |z Minnesota.; Libel and slander |z United States.; Journalists -- United States.; Minnesota |x Politics and government.; Manuscripts for publication.; Populism |z Minnesota.; Political assassination |z Minnesota.; Screenplays; Research (document genres).; Communist Party of the United States of America; Liggett, Walter W., (Walter William), 1886-1935; Minnesota. Governor (1931-1936: Olson); Olson, Floyd Björnstjerne, 1891-1936; Daily Worker (New York); Farmer-Labor Party (Minn.); Evans, Mark Walter
- Bibliographic information on the Nonpartisan League (Box 1)
- Spurred to Victory, Walter W. Liggett (Box 1)
- Articles from the Modern Monthly, Walter W. Liggett (Box 1)
- Newspaper clippings about Walter W. Liggett (Box 1)
- The Skookum Kid's Last Bluff, Walter W. Liggett (Box 1)
- Articles in "Plain Talk" re: prohibition, Walter W. Liggett (Box 1)
- Memos on Gov. Frazier (North Dakota) and coal miners' strike (Box 1)
- PhD dissertation on the Nonpartisan League, Stanley Wasson (Box 1)
- Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett, Marda L. Woodbury, correspondence re: publication (Box 1)
- Research from the Minnesota Historical Society (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and the Nebraska State Historical Society (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and Federal Agencies (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and FBI (Box 1)
- Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett, Marda L. Woodbury, draft (Box 1)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, articles and essays (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and the Fleischer-Rosenblatt family (Box 1)
- Notebook: research notes for Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and the National Archives (Box 2)
- Information re: murder of Walter W. Liggett (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and research assistants (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and David J. Rience (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and researchers (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and Department of the Treasury (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and Washington State Library (Box 2)
- Information on Pasco, Washington (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and Fleischer-Rosenblatt family (Box 2)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, draft (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and the Ask family (Box 2)
- Liggett Root history, articles and letters from the Sons of Liberty and DAR (Box 2)
- Research information from Minnesota (Box 2)
- The Political Career of Floyd B. Olson, George H. Mayer (copy) (Box 3)
- Research information from the National Archives (Box 3)
- Biographical Dictionary of the American Left (copies of chapters) (Box 3)
- Research on the Minnesota Farmer-Labor Party (Box 3)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, bibliography (Box 3)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, drafts and notes separated by chapter (Box 3)
- Papers and articles on Walter W. Liggett (Box 3)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, articles and publicity (Box 3)
- Newspapers announcing Walter W. Liggett's death (Box 3)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, draft with editorial notes (Box 3)
- Masters of Capital in America, John Moody and George Kibbe Turner, (copies of chapters) (Box 3)
- C. A. Lindberg, speeches on banking and currency given in Congress (Box 4)
- C. A. Lindberg, pamphlets and articles (copies) (Box 4)
- New York Times articles on "Prairie Radicalism" (copies) (Box 4)
- Series of articles on Charles Lindberg, Sr. and links with Bolshevism and Populism (copies) (Box 4)
- New York Times articles on banking and the Federal Reserve (copies) (Box 4)
- The Federal Reserve System, Its Purposes and Functions, S.W. Adams (copy) (Box 4)
- Unnamed thesis on the Nonpartisan League (copy) (Box 4)
- The United Front, essays on the struggle against fascism (copy) (Box 4)
- Banking and Currency and the Money Trust, Charles A. Lindberg (copy) (Box 4)
- Why is Your Country at War and What Happens to You After the War and Related Subjects, Charles A. Lindberg (copy) (Box 4)
- The Economic Pinch, Charles A. Lindberg (copy) (Box 4)
- Series of newspaper articles by A.C. Townley and Walter W. Liggett on Gov. Floyd B. Olson (copies) (Box 4)
- Articles and essays, Thomas Lamont (copies) (Box 4)
- Account of the murder of Walter W. Liggett, partial draft of Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury (Box 4)
- Edits to Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, edits made by John Haynes of the Library of Congress (Box 4)
- Watercolor painting of a boy in a hat by "EWV" (Box 4)
- Issue of Common Sense by Walter W. Liggett (Box 4)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, draft with editorial comments (Box 5)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, notes on Magnus Johnson and Floyd B. Olson (Box 5)
- Tomorrow is a Day, A Story of People in Politics, John Beecher (copy with notes) (Box 5)
- Minnesota Farmer-Laborism, The Third-Party Alternative, Millard Gieska (copy) (Box 5)
- Hjalmar Petersen of Minnesota, Steven J. Keillor (copy) (Box 5)
- Floyd Olson: The Years Prior to his Governorship Steven D. Jansen (copy) (Box 5)
- State-Level Radicalism and the Nationalization of American Politics: The Case of the Minnesota Farmer-Labor Party, Richard Martin Valelly (copy) (Box 5)
- The Progressive Movement of 1924, Kenneth MacKay (copy) (Box 5)
- Research on the Farmer-Labor Party (Box 5)
- Photographs related to the murder of Walter W. Liggett (Box 5)
- Newspaper reviews of Walter W. Liggett's work (copies) (Box 5)
- Articles by Walter W. Liggett related to aviation (copies) (Box 5)
- All Bets are Off, Walter W. Liggett (Box 5)
- Blazing Buttes, Walter W. Liggett (Box 5)
- Research on Communists in the Farmer-Labor Party and Minnesota (Box 5)
- Obituaries of Floyd Olson (copies) (Box 5)
- Petitions sent to Floyd Olson (copies) (Box 5)
- Angry Voices, Left-of-Center Politics in the New Deal Era, Donald R. McCoy (copy) (Box 5)
- FBI reports on Floyd Olson (Box 5)
- St. Paul Dispatch articles on the murder of Walter W. Liggett (copies) (Box 5)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and book reviewers (Box 6)
- Correspondence: Mardy Woodbury and speaking/publicity venues (Box 6)
- "The Editor Who Knew Too Much," in Bay Area Writer, Kara Huebner, review of Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury (copy) (Box 6)
- Notes on the Midwest American newspaper (Box 6)
- "Researching an Assassination." In IRE Journal, copies and notes (Box 6)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, editorial notes (Box 6)
- "Freedom of the Press and Phonokus Bolognus: Minneapolis's Teamster Strike of 1934," Marda L. Woodbury, draft (Box 6)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and Kenneth Varnold re: play on Liggett family (Box 6)
- "Poison Spots of Crime," Marda L. Woodbury, research and draft (Box 6)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, publicity inquiries (Box 6)
- Advertisement materials for Even Management Services, a Publicity Firm (Box 6)
- Notes on the Liggett family by Walter Liggett, Jr. (Box 6)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, cover design (Box 6)
- Connoisseur Magazine, Correspondence and copies related to Marda L. Woodbury's objection to the use of a photograph of Walter and Edith Liggett in the magazine (Box 6)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and various publications, writing to object to articles written about Walter W. Liggett (Box 6)
- Marda L. Woodbury, television interview notes (Box 6)
- Materials related to theories concerning the attack on Peal Harbor and the assassination of JFK (Box 6)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and various historians re: Stopping the Presses (Box 6)
- Informational literature re: research at a public library (Box 6)
- Screenplay: Correspondence between Marda L. Woodbury and Charlene Richards (Box 7)
- Screenplay: 5 pages of screenplay by Marda L. Woodbury and Mark Evans (Box 7)
- Screenplay: formatting guide (Box 7)
- Screenplay: Correspondence between Mark Evans and Charlene Richards (Box 7)
- Research on Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon (Box 7)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and Alison Aten (publisher) re: publicity for Stopping the Presses (Box 7)
- Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, marketing plan from the University of Minnesota Press (Box 7)
- Biographical information on Marda L. Woodbury (Box 7)
- Correspondence: Marda L. Woodbury and various book reviewers re: sending copies of Stopping the Presses to potential reviewers (Box 7)
- Christmas newsletters sent by Marda L. Woodbury (Box 7)
- Research: articles and essays re: freedom of the press (Box 7)
- Research: newspaper articles re: newspapers in the 1930s and 1940s (Box 7)
- Screenplay: notes on "Liggett" by Marda L. Woodbury and Mark Evans (loose pages and a notebook) (Box 7)
- Screenplay: "Liggett," 153 pg. draft (Box 7)
- Screenplay: "Liggett," multiple copies with editorial notes (Box 7)
- Screenplay: "Liggett," 119 pg. bound copy (Box 7)
- Screenplay: "Liggett," page-by-page documentation and ideas for casting (Box 7)
- "Plain Talk," vol. IV, Number 5, notes taken about issue on a separate sheet (Box 7)
- Research: Tom Mooney trial (1916 bomb explosion), copies of articles and parts of books (Box 8)
- Research: Muckraking journalism, newspaper articles (copies) (Box 8)
- Research: Murder, Inc. and Buggsey Siegel, copies of newspaper articles (Box 8)
- Research: homicide investigations related to Walter Liggett (Box 8)
- Research: Walter Liggett murder, newspaper articles (Box 8)
- Research: Freedom of the Press and ANPA (American Newspaper Publishers Association) (Box 8)
- Research: notes related to Joe Murphy connected to Tom Mooney trial (Box 8)
- Research: Woodrow Wilson and WWI, articles from newspapers and notes (Box 8)
- Research: Daily Worker, archival records (copies) (Box 8)
- Family life of Walter Liggett and divorce from Norma Joanna Liggett (copies) (Box 8)
- Research: Communist Party in Minnesota (Box 8)
- Research: Crime statistics in the US and in Minnesota (Box 8)
- Research: Kid Cann (real name: Isadore Bluenfeld), suspect in Liggett murder investigation (Box 8)
- Research: Kid Cann, articles and notes on connections with the Mafia, FBI files, white slavery trafficking charge (Box 9)
- Research: Carley Report, Report of the Senate (investigation committee) (Box 9)
- Research: Prof. Herman Chapman (Yale), friend of Walter Liggett, archival materials (copies) (Box 9)
- Research: biographical information on Minnesota Labor Party leaders (Box 9)
- Correspondence: Mark Evans and Birch Research Inc. (Box 9)
- Research: Minnesota Historical Society, Joseph Burnquist Papers (copies) (Box 9)
- Research: Correspondence between Edith and Walter Liggett and George Calverton (Box 9)
- Research: Newspaper organizations (Box 9)
- Research: beating of Walter Liggett, copies of newspaper articles (Box 9)
- Notes and draft of Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, on Elmer Benson (banker/political leader) (Box 9)
- Notepad with notes on filing research for Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury (Box 9)
- Walter Liggett biographical information (copies) (Box 9)
- Research: ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union) and connection with Walter Liggett (Box 9)
- Research: Agrarian Radicalism (Box 9)
- Edith Liggett, "The Joke's on Us" (7 pg. short story) (Box 9)
- Research: Walter Liggett and The Daily Alaskan (Box 9)
- Draft of "The Cops Arrive," chapter in Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury (Box 9)
- Sympathy cards from the memorial service for Edith Liggett (Box 9)
- Edith Liggett: articles and notes written by her after Walter Liggett's death (Box 9)
- "Walter Liggett" by Edith Liggett, 12 pg. recollection of his life (Box 9)
- Research: the Federal Reserve, newspaper articles (copies) (Box 9)
- Research: University Archives of Wayne State University on the Federated Press (copies) (Box 9)
- Research: trial of Walter Liggett (1934, abduction of two minor girls) (Box 9)
- Edith Liggett: letters, photographs, and postcards sent to friends and family (Box 10)
- "Edith Liggett" by Marda L. Woodbury, a biographical essay (Box 10)
- "Myself, Outline of one life experience" by Edith Liggett, a two page recollection of having children (Box 10)
- Edith Liggett, account of Walter Liggett's "Mexican divorce" and subsequent marriage to Edith (copy) (Box 10)
- Research: Frank Ellis (labor organizer accused to sexual misconduct with the same two girls involved in the Walter Liggett trial), notes, articles from newspapers, court documents (Box 10)
- Research: farm organization articles and periodicals (copies) (Box 10)
- Research: Farmer-Labor articles and notes (copies) (Box 10)
- Research: Annette Fawcett, friend of Minnesota gangsters in the 1930s, including Kid Cann; police records, newspaper articles (copies) (Box 10)
- FBI files on Walter Liggett (copies) (Box 10)
- Research: Howard Guilford's murder (newspaper editor from Minnesota), newspaper articles and notes FBI files on Abe Harries (copies) (Box 10)
- Research: Clarence Hathaway, Farmer-Labor Party organizer, notes, articles from newspapers, and FBI files (copies) (Box 10)
- Research: Haymarket Riot (Box 10)
- Walter W. Liggett, The Rise of Herbert Hoover, responses and reactions in letters and newspaper articles (copies) (Box 10)
- Edith Liggett, "Walter Liggett," a short biographical essay on his life, copies with editorial notes (Box 10)
- Walter W. Liggett, "Charles Ward – Success Story," short essay on the gangster (Box 10)
- Walter W. Liggett, "Prairie Caesar," short essay on political movements in Minnesota, critical of Gov. Olson (Box 10)
- Research: Gag law and ACLU involvement, notes, articles (copies) (Box 10)
- Research: Joseph Gilbert (member of Nonpartisan League) (Box 10)
- Research: Jake Lingle, writer from the Chicago Tribune, murdered by gangsters in 1930 (Box 10)
- Research: Arthur Kasherman, journalist murdered in 1945 (Box 10)
- Research: Labor organizing in Minneapolis (Box 10)
- Charles Lindbergh: newspaper articles (copies) about 1918 near-lynching (Box 10)
- Mark Evans, articles and essays (Box 11)
- Research: Nonpartisan League (Box 11)
- The Mid-West American (2 large bound volumes), newspaper archives of articles (Box 11)
- One Man – Wendell Willkie, C. Nelson Sparks, bound book/biography (Box 11)
- Research: Mooney trial, copies of newspaper articles and notes, copies of archival materials from the Bancroft Library (Box 11)
- Research: state of Minnesota and politics (Box 11)
- "Remembered Haven," Marda L. Woodbury, essay on the author's childhood and growing up in many places (Box 11)
- Research: crime and gangsters in Minnesota, newspaper articles and FBI reports (copies), notes (Box 11)
- Edith Liggett: photographs and cards (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Indian Stories", mostly typewritten: "Prairie Napoleon," "PhD in Indian Folk Lore," "Geronimo," (Box 12)
- "The Resettled Indians," "I Married a White Man," "Grey Owl," and "When is an Indian not an Indian?" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Life and Budgets" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Look Savage, Please" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Madonna House" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Malice Domestic" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Morning Chimes and Chocolate Rabbits" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Mother Love" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Nine Million Americans are Old" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Pastorale American" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "The Gifted Child" (Box 12)
- Mathilda Brown (Liggett): "Spring Blizzard" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Tante Elka" (Box 12)
- "From Rags to Riches: Sophie Lyons", also titled as, "Virtue is its own Reward" (Box 12)
- Correspondence: Edith Liggett and various literary agents and publishers (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Wanted – Glamorous Movie Heroes" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Winner Take All" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Whiteoak Mode Shops" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Outlines" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Adoption Racket" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "False Accusation" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "MacDowell – Coal and Lumber" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Miss Lissa Inga" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "The Blind and the Babies Need Care" aka "Bertha Harrison Story" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Blinded Police Detective" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "The Case is Solved!" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "City Girl" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Charley Fly – Photographer" aka "Arizona Indians" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Death Passed Me By" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Falashas (Jews of Abyssinia)" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Families Are Like That" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Fight Story" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Hardware and Doughnuts" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "I Was a Fat Girl" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Indian Story" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Lady's Maid" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "The Lampert Family" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Marm Mandelbaum" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "How to Write Detective Stories" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Windows are Better than Eyeglasses" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Who's Afraid" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "White Morocco" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "We Were Afraid" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "We Ran Away" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Viva Mama" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Vic" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Detective Dardy's Day in Court" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "That Lethal Weapon – The Auto" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Somebody had to be Hurt" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Runaway" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Pay Clinic" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Plain Girl" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Right Cross Double Cross" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Patterson" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "No Grounds" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Mismatched Neal" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Ministering Angel (Sarah Chesham) (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Mama" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Mid Winter Madness" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Leg Report" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Boy Delinquent" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Must our Cities be so Dirty" by Dr. Mortimer Sherman" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Bertha Harrison Story Resume" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "True Stories", queries and notes (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "My Son was Killed" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "About Selina" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Accused of Murder" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Always Secure" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Apartment Super's Wife" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "A Backyard for Jimmy" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Bright October" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Edwin Graham" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Fear Rode With Us" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Free Lunch in Papa's Saloon" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Good Training" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Grace of God" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Harriet McIntosh, now Mrs. Gilbert Kissell" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Deep Winter" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Drama in Everyday Life" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Deep Winter" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Bright October" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Beautiful Forever" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Career Woman" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Change Your Job Change Your Life" (Box 12)
- Edith Liggett: "Crazy is as Crazy Does" (Box 12)
- New York Call: articles on women and fascism (copies) (Box 13)
- New York Times: articles (copies) (Box 13)
- Midwest Organizer: articles and notes on the Frank Ellis case (copies) (Box 13)
- Organized Farmer: articles (copies)` (Box 13)
- Plain Talk: Notes, copies of articles, and copies of Time articles on Plain Talk (Box 13)
- Rochester Post-Bulletin: articles (copies) (Box 13)
- St. Louis Post-Dispatch: articles (copies) (Box 13)
- St. Paul Dispatch: articles on Walter Liggett (copies) (Box 13)